#### **CONTACT ME AT:**

615-668-4657



justinav38@gmail.com



github.com/justinavickers



linkedin.com/in/justina-vickers

Junior Full-Stack Developer

**JUSTINA VICKERS** 

## **ABOUT ME**

I took a different path in life, and started my own cleaning business with my twin sister after high school. We ran the business together for three years and decided to take the skills we had learned and move on to other opportunities. I took a position at Jimmy Johns and, in one year, worked my way up from cashier to GM. Although the company encouraged further growth, I found myself facing a choice; take on more responsibility (requiring me to move out of state) or stay in Nashville in my current position. As a native Nashvillian, I knew moving wasn't the right option for me, so I found myself looking for a new career. I wanted a career with room to grow. where the possibilities would be endless. My family kept telling me to try software development. Everything I learned about software made it the obvious choice. I joined the Jumpstart program at NSS, and fell in love. My family had been right all along! Shortly after finishing the Jumpstart program I applied for the 6 month course and was accepted. I am lucky to have the opportunity to continually learn and grow with this career. The challenges motivate me to expand my knowledge, feed my creativity, and become a better developer.

## **PROJECTS**

Trail Boxes: Front-End Capstone As an aspiring Appalachian Trail thru hiker, I have realized there aren't any good platforms to organize your drop boxes for a several month journey. Sure, we have spreadsheets but those can get easily disorganized and can be confusing for people to use. I wanted to make a single page app that will allow the user to easily see all of the their planned boxes and the contents in each one.

# **EXPERIENCE**

Nashville Software School: Junior Full-Stack Developer 2018-2019

- **Problem Solving**
- Front-End and Back-End Development
- Daily hands on application of OOP fundamentals through group and individual projects
- Created single page applications in Javascript using React.js framework, CSS3 and Bootstrap
- · Worked with the jQuery Javascript library for DOM manipulation
- Utilized Grunt to automate bundling of modules and JavaScript linting
- Project management/tracking with GitHub Issue Tracking
- Created single page application for a user to chat with friends, add tasks and save articles.
- Created a single page application for tourists coming to Nashville. The user can make an itinerary for a park, meetup, concert or restaurant they want to visit. This was accomplished by accessing data through four external API's using asynchronous fetch calls in JavaScript. Using this data, search results are dynamically displayed on the DOM.

Jimmy Johns: General Manager 2014-2017

- Managed a team of 30 people including part-time and full-time employees.
- · Performed all manager duties for staff including hiring, terminations, onboarding and performance reviews.
- Used team building exercises to promote a sense of cohesiveness among the staff.
- Managed all inventory, budgeting, and overhead costs.
- Trained and audited all staff members.
- Held regular sit downs with managers to discuss the implementation of personal improvement plans for the purpose of bettering overall morale and confidence.

Twinkleen: Co-Owner 2011-2014

- Responsible for creating company website using Go Daddy.
- Managed customer relationships including face to face sales consultation, company wide scheduling, and client focused quality control check-ins.
- In charge of hiring, firing, and training of all employees.

#### ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

Nashville Software School: Full-Stack Developer 2018-2019